{"Topic": "Economy", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "of General Knowledge Questions on Economics and Indian Economy", "op1": "Seasonal unemployment", "op2": "Structural unemployment", "op3": "Disguised unemployment", "op4": "Cyclical unemployment", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "When the productive capacity of the economic system of a State is inadequate to create sufficient  number of jobs, it is called", "op1": "The Reserve Bank of India", "op2": "The Planning Commission", "op3": "The Finance Ministry", "op4": "The Securities and Exchange board of India"}, {"Question": "Fiscal policy in India is formulated by", "op1": "Most favoured nation treatment", "op2": "Lowering trade barriers with negotiations", "op3": "Providing financial support to the countries having deficit balance of payments", "op4": "Discouraging unfair trade practices such as anti-dumping and export subsides", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one among the following is not a clause of World Trade Organization?", "op1": "The World Bank", "op2": "The Reserve Bank of India", "op3": "The World Trade Organization", "op4": "The International Monetary Fund", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Special Drawings Rights (SDRs) relate to", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "2 only", "op3": "2 and 3", "op4": "1 and 2", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following measures should be taken when an economy is going through inflationary  pressures?", "op1": "Sales of a firm", "op2": "Salary of employees", "op3": "Exports of the IT sector", "op4": "Sale of land", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "West Africa", "op2": "East Africa", "op3": "North Africa", "op4": "Central Africa", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "e:", "op1": "No licence is required for import", "op2": "Manufacturing and service activities are allowed", "op3": "No permission for subcontracting", "op4": "No routine examination of cargo for export/import by customs authorities", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "National income ignores", "op1": "China-USA-India-Brazil-Mexico", "op2": "USA-China-India-Brazil-Mexico", "op3": "China-USA-Brazil-India-Mexico", "op4": "USA-Mexico-China-India-Brazil", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The TEAM-9 initiative is a techno economic cooperation venture between India and eight countries of", "op1": "Mahalanobis", "op2": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "op3": "VKRV Rao", "op4": "Sardar Patel", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one among the following is not true for Special Economic Zones?", "op1": "Natural resources", "op2": "Capital formation", "op3": "Size of the market", "op4": "All of the above"}, {"Question": "According to Goldman Sachs\u2019 review of emerging economies, by 2050 which one of the following would be the order of the largest economies in the world?", "op1": "any money making activity", "op2": "any laborious activity", "op3": "any profit-making activity", "op4": "any productive activity", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who estimated the National Income for the first time in India?", "op1": "Planning Commission", "op2": "Finance Commission", "op3": "Reserve Bank of India", "op4": "Commercial Banks", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "", "op1": "Gold Reserve System", "op2": "Proportional Reserve System", "op3": "Convertible Currency System", "op4": "Minimum Reserve System", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Economic development depends on", "op1": "Absolute Poverty", "op2": "Relative Poverty", "op3": "Urban Poverty", "op4": "Rural Poverty", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "National income is generated from"}, {"Question": "Money supply is governed by the"}, {"Question": "The present Indian monetary system is based on"}, {"Question": "Full convertibility of a rupee means", "op1": "Purchase of foreign exchange for rupees freely", "op2": "Payment for imports in terms of rupees", "op3": "Repayment of loans in terms of rupees", "op4": "Determination of rate of exchange between rupee and foreign currencies freely by the market forces of demand and supply", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "India is called a mixed economy because of the existence of", "op1": "1, 4", "op2": "1, 2", "op3": "3, 4", "op4": "2, 4", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The term stagflation refers to a situation where", "op1": "Growth has no relation with the change in prices", "op2": "Rate of growth and prices both are decreasing", "op3": "Rate of growth is faster than the rate of price increase", "op4": "Rate of growth is slower than the rate of price increase"}, {"Question": "Revealed Preference Theory was propounded by", "op1": "Adam Smith", "op2": "Marshall", "op3": "P. A. Samuelson", "op4": "J. S. Mill"}, {"Question": "Gross Domestic Product is defined as the value of all", "op1": "Goods produced in an economy in a year", "op2": "Goods and services produced in an economy in a year", "op3": "Final goods produced in an economy in a year", "op4": "Final goods and services produced in an economy in a year", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "An exceptional demand curve is one that moves", "op1": "Upward to the right", "op2": "Downward to the right", "op3": "Horizontally", "op4": "Vertically", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Production function explains the relationship between", "op1": "Initial inputs and ultimate output", "op2": "Inputs and ultimate consumption", "op3": "Output and consumption", "op4": "Output and exports", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The Draft of the Five Year Plans in India is approved by the", "op1": "National Development Council", "op2": "Planning Commission", "op3": "National Productivity Council", "op4": "Ministry of Finance", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In Economics the terms \u2018Utility\u2019 and \u2018Usefulness\u2019 have", "op1": "Same meaning", "op2": "Different meaning", "op3": "Opposite meaning", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Nature of unemployment in agriculture in India is", "op1": "Only seasonal", "op2": "Only disguised", "op3": "Both (a) and (b)", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The terms \"Micro Economics\" and \"Macro Economics\" were coined by", "op1": "Alfred Marshall", "op2": "Ragner Nurkse", "op3": "Ragner Frisch", "op4": "J.M. Keynes", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "o see G.K. Questions on Banking"}]}